<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Informes de Inteligencia on Intel Center</title><link>https://mcasrom.github.io/intel_center/post/</link><description>Recent content in Informes de Inteligencia on Intel Center</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>es</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mcasrom.github.io/intel_center/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>📌 MANUAL: Interpretación de Nodos y Mapas</title><link>https://mcasrom.github.io/intel_center/post/guia-interpretacion-nodos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mcasrom.github.io/intel_center/post/guia-interpretacion-nodos/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="protocolo-de-lectura"&gt;Protocolo de Lectura&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este documento sirve como base para la interpretación de los datos dinámicos del Intel Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="1-dinámica-del-mapa"&gt;1. Dinámica del Mapa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intensidad:&lt;/strong&gt; El radio de los círculos representa el volumen de cables procesados en las últimas 24 horas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Normalización:&lt;/strong&gt; Un valor de 15 indica un flujo informativo estable. Valores superiores a 30 sugieren una crisis en desarrollo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="2-nodos-de-inteligencia"&gt;2. Nodos de Inteligencia&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eurasia:&lt;/strong&gt; Monitorización vía TASS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medio Oriente:&lt;/strong&gt; Cobertura Al Jazeera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asia-Pacífico:&lt;/strong&gt; Indicadores Nikkei Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Américas/Europa:&lt;/strong&gt; Análisis DW, BBC y The Guardian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="3-ciclo-de-vida-del-dato"&gt;3. Ciclo de Vida del Dato&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los informes bajo este manual se generan automáticamente cada 6 horas. La base de datos se purga cada 30 días para mantener la relevancia operativa.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Resumen Inteligencia 2026-02-05</title><link>https://mcasrom.github.io/intel_center/post/2026-02-05-informe-inteligencia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mcasrom.github.io/intel_center/post/2026-02-05-informe-inteligencia/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Expulsion of Russian firms from Venezuela, US sanctions after Anchorage: Lavrov statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: Germany news: Merz meets with Saudi crown prince&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Saudi Arabia opens stock market to all foreign investors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukraine, Russia to pore over memoranda exchanged at talks — Foreign Ministry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia, Ukraine to agree on date of new round of talks after memorandums are studied&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Belarus’ defense ministry expects to strengthen cooperation with Pakistan significantly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Frequency of meetings on Ukraine talks can’t be strictly standardized — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Pakistani PM asks Putin to help resolve conflict with India — aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia to take all measures to solve crime related to attacks on airfields — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: France, Belgium oppose ban on gas imports from Russia to EU — Politico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Putin’s stance on death penalty moratorium remains firm — Kremlin spokesman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Europe’s gas stocks replenishment slower than usual, situation becomes tense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Japan reports record-low birth rate in 2024, ministry reveals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia takes measures proceeding from Kiev’s attacks on peaceful facilities — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Diamond prices mixed in May — industry agency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Crimean bridge unaffected by Kiev’s attack, Kremlin spokesman says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Poland&amp;rsquo;s capacity to deliver arms to Ukraine heavily constrained — paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia not interested in arms race with Europe, European Parliament member says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Thai election due on Sunday: Three key points to watch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: China&amp;rsquo;s provinces ease growth targets, fueling expectations of national cut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Indonesia logs 5.1% GDP growth in 2025 but outlook remains downcast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Family offices eye niche strategies, impact investing in emerging managers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump and Xi talk Taiwan at dicey time for Taipei&amp;rsquo;s defense spending&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Yum China aims to capture &amp;rsquo;early signs&amp;rsquo; of improved consumer appetite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: India&amp;rsquo;s $166m bid to modernize critical mineral recycling takes shape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Sony lifts full-year profit outlook on chip demand, IP gain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: TSMC to make advanced chips for AI at 2nd Japan plant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: HP, Dell, Acer and Asus mull using Chinese memory chips amid supply crunch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Jailed Vietnam airline mogul is back to work with South Korean talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Nepal polls test old guard as Gen Z protest reshapes political landscape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s stock market rout smokes out long-standing manipulation issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Japan&amp;rsquo;s DNP to sell photo printers, auto parts in India&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: US, China and Russia erode the rules-based order, says Human Rights Watch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Boletín: Primer ataque de EE.UU. y aliados árabes contra Estado Islámico en Siria y otras noticias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Estrato 1, estrato 6: cómo los colombianos hablan de sí mismos divididos en clases sociales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Las dos vidas de Cantinflas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Santos: &amp;ldquo;No le estoy dando el país a las FARC&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Fernández denuncia que con caso &amp;ldquo;fondos buitres&amp;rdquo; quieren poner de rodillas a Argentina&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: ¿Por qué internet en Venezuela es tan lento?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Vuelven a posponer el juicio a Leopoldo López&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Chile: roban US$3,3 millones a la casa de empeño &amp;ldquo;Tía Rica&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Los consejos del Nobel mexicano que descubrió gases del agujero de ozono&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Boletín: más de 130.000 sirios kurdos cruzan a Turquía huyendo de Estado Islámico y otras noticias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: ¿Cómo se convirtió Cuba en una potencia humanitaria?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Cómo operan las mafias del multimillonario negocio de la madera ilegal en Perú&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Los inodoros que ayudan a los haitianos a cultivar sus alimentos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Un inodoro para combatir enfermedades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM]&lt;/strong&gt;: Maduro anuncia un plan de desarme de civiles en Venezuela&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: Woody Allen, a Florida mansion rulebook and a Paris ‘wife hunt’: stories you may have missed from the Epstein files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: Brad Karp: Wall Street law firm boss resigns after emails to Epstein released&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: New York City and Illinois join WHO network after Trump pulls US out of global health body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: Savannah Guthrie releases video appealing for proof her missing mother is alive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: Tulsi Gabbard reportedly oversaw probe of Puerto Rico voting machines last year – as it happened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: Nancy Pelosi warns press freedom is ‘under siege’ after arrest of journalist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump news at a glance: president hints at ‘softer touch’ on immigration as federal drawdown planned in Minnesota&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: California can use a new congressional map in November, supreme court rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: Minnesota girl, 10, released from ICE custody after a month in detention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: Thursday briefing: W​ill the Epstein ​files ​threaten ​Peter Mandelson’s ​legacy​?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: US congressional report explores option of not delivering any Aukus nuclear submarines to Australia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: Florida bill seeks to ban use of ‘West Bank’ in schools and state agencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: Steve Bannon calls for immigration agents at polling sites during midterms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: The Guardian view on Epstein, power and accountability: full transparency is the least survivors deserve | Editorial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[USA_NORTE]&lt;/strong&gt;: What is happening in Fulton county is a warning to America | Jamil Smith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Silver futures price down over 11%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Almaz-Antey to showcase latest air defense systems at exhibition in Riyadh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian stocks down as main trading session opens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia believes agreement on Ukraine should include Donbass recognition — TASS source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: UAE talks discuss ceasefire, territories — source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukraine’s military shells Russia’s borderline Kursk Region 16 times over past day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: End of Russia-US nuclear accords: on Feb 5 world left without New START Treaty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Polish PM arrives in Kiev for talks with Zelensky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Talks on Ukraine continue in Abu Dhabi in trilateral format — TASS source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Nearly 100 drones attack Russian regions overnight: aftermath&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Power plant accident leaves eastern Cuba without electricity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia surprised by US sanctions against oil companies after Anchorage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia not imposing itself as mediator between Iran, US — Lavrov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump to make decision on New START when deems appropriate — media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian companies openly forced out of Venezuela after events in republic — Lavrov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Epstein’s help sought in bid to meet Chuck Schumer, files reveal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Here’s why Israel is allowing record murder rates in its Palestinian towns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Boycotting India at T20 World Cup to support Bangladesh: Pakistan PM Sharif&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia-Ukraine war live: Second day of US-led war talks start in UAE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: South Sudan hospital hit by government air strike, MSF says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Panama’s president hits back after China threat in canal ports row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Bitcoin plunge continues, erasing gains since Trump’s election&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: ‘We have to rebuild’: Mozambique flood victims persevere in face of loss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: LIVE: US, Iran set to hold talks in Oman after barrage of threats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Who are the past winners, and what’s the history of the T20 World Cup?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Italy probes suspect in Sarajevo ‘sniper tourism’ during Bosnia war: Report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Questions after Iran’s government releases victim list in protest killings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: UN warns of humanitarian collapse in Cuba as US seeks to block oil supplies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: ‘Country of the blind’: How will Bangladesh remember Muhammad Yunus?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Zelenskyy reveals 55,000 Ukrainian soldiers killed fighting against Russia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: How US Project Vault challenges China&amp;rsquo;s rare-earth dominance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: Germany: Icy rain halts departures at Berlin airport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: Germany updates: Merz meets with Saudi crown prince&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: China’s Xi holds calls with Trump, and Putin, on same day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukraine updates: Trilateral talks enter second day in UAE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: US wants to establish critical minerals trade bloc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: New START: Last US-Russia nuclear treaty expires, raising fears of new global arms race&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: Winter Olympics begin quietly with curling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: US, Iran to hold talks in Oman on Friday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;lsquo;Doomsday Clock&amp;rsquo;: The US-Russia New START deal is ending&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: US: Would-be Trump assassin gets life without parole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: Turkey&amp;rsquo;s textile industry crushed by China and Bangladesh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: Italy says it has foiled Russian Olympic cyberattacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: Nigeria: Extremists kill over 100 in western villages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Europa_DW]&lt;/strong&gt;: ICE to reduce numbers in Minnesota, but operations go on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Resumen Inteligencia 2026-02-04</title><link>https://mcasrom.github.io/intel_center/post/2026-02-04-informe-inteligencia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mcasrom.github.io/intel_center/post/2026-02-04-informe-inteligencia/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia jails stand-up comic Artemy Ostani over war joke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia’s Putin holds video call with China’s Xi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Israeli strikes kill more than 20 in Gaza, shatter ‘ceasefire’ myth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Japan&amp;rsquo;s 3 top banks on track to earn record profits for fiscal year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Southeast Asia IPOs rebound in second half, raising $4.5bn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Japan, US insurers snap up Lloyd&amp;rsquo;s operators on war risk expertise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: China money rattles gold market in volatile week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Analysis: Chinese power struggle sends ripples through Japan&amp;rsquo;s election&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: OSCE chairman to visit Russia as representative of organization in deep crisis — envoy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US wants to secure oil access for years, making Venezuela crucial — VP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Bank of Russia sets dollar rate at 76.91 rubles for February 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kiev authorities actively assist terrorists in Africa — envoy to UN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Argentina moves to extradite Maduro from US — portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian envoy to UN urges action against IS terrorists&amp;rsquo; use of Starlink terminals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Annual inflation in Russia gearing up to 6.45% from January 27 to February 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Il-76 cargo plane from Russia arrives in Cuba — Fidel Castro Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia strongly condemns assassination of Gaddafi’s son&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kiev to receive first disbursements from 90 bln euro loan in second quarter — EU Council&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: EU representatives agree 90 bln funding mechanism for Kiev — Reuters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia supports Cuba amid intensifying pressure — Foreign Ministry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: OSCE bigwigs coming to Moscow for talks on how to bring end to Ukraine conflict&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: US announces proposed critical mineral trading bloc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Killing of Saif Gaddafi removes alternative to Libya’s rival governments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Mixed emotions among Palestinians as Rafah crossing partially reopens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump hails ‘excellent’ phone call with China’s Xi amid trade tensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gaza on the agenda as Turkiye’s Erdogan meets Egypt’s el-Sisi in Cairo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian shelling kills seven in Ukrainian market, clouding Abu Dhabi talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: India-China relations may provide important impetus to future of BRICS — expert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukraine, Russia to pore over memoranda exchanged at talks — Foreign Ministry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia, Ukraine to agree on date of new round of talks after memorandums are studied&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Belarus’ defense ministry expects to strengthen cooperation with Pakistan significantly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Frequency of meetings on Ukraine talks can’t be strictly standardized — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Pakistani PM asks Putin to help resolve conflict with India — aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia to take all measures to solve crime related to attacks on airfields — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: France, Belgium oppose ban on gas imports from Russia to EU — Politico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Putin’s stance on death penalty moratorium remains firm — Kremlin spokesman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Europe’s gas stocks replenishment slower than usual, situation becomes tense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Japan reports record-low birth rate in 2024, ministry reveals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia takes measures proceeding from Kiev’s attacks on peaceful facilities — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Diamond prices mixed in May — industry agency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Crimean bridge unaffected by Kiev’s attack, Kremlin spokesman says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Poland&amp;rsquo;s capacity to deliver arms to Ukraine heavily constrained — paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia not interested in arms race with Europe, European Parliament member says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: EU Council confirms refusal of Hungary, Czech Republic, Slovakia to fund Kiev — document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: EU hinders Russia’s, US’s efforts on Ukrainian settlement — envoy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Security guarantees being floated for Ukraine preclude peace deal — Lavrov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: India’s purchases of Russian hydrocarbons benefit both countries — Russian diplomat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Five tank cars on fire in Tambov Region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: US border security chief withdrawing 700 immigration agents from Minnesota&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: India seeks to deepen ties with Russia, expert says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: IDF expresses regret over harm to uninvolved persons in strike on southern Gaza&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Current inflation expectations at 13.7% likely to be peak — Bank of Russia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: FACTBOX: Strategic arms agreements between the Soviet Union/Russia and the US&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukraine dialogue continues, but Europe seeks to rework US proposals — Lavrov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US to establish alliance for production of critical minerals with fixed prices — JD Vance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Can India switch from Russian to Venezuelan oil, as Trump wants?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Epstein files reveal web of relationships among rich and powerful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Epstein, Israel’s Barak discussed ‘gigantic’ consultancy sums paid to Blair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Roscosmos opens cosmonaut recruitment, taking applications again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Juan Antonio Samaranch re-elected as IOC vice president&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: First day of resumed talks on Ukraine concludes in Abu Dhabi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Supercam UAVs fitted with flight safety software similar to Flightradar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kalashnikov introduces major software update to its SKAT-350M UAV last year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ivanov voluntarily steps down from his post as special presidential envoy — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Libya’s top prosecutor launches probe into Saif al-Islam Gaddafi’s killing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Mediators propose framework for crucial Iran-US talks this week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Epstein files show how West treats children — Russian Foreign Ministry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukrainian delegation’s core composition at Abu Dhabi talks unchanged — paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Putin dismisses his special envoy on environmental protection, ecology, and transport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian troops liberate two communities in Ukraine operation over past day — top brass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukraine’s energy crisis rooted in corruption, Russian diplomat says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Epstein files, Zelensky follows in Nazi footsteps: Foreign Ministry statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: German exports to Russia down 5.3% in April month-on-month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Khrunichev Center begins production of three Angara-A5M rockets for launching ROS modules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gagauzia head faces court: recent developments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump-Musk clash costs both hefty sums in one day — media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Press review: Europe seeks to block US-Russia thaw as Russia eyes role in US-Iran talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Israel to continue striking Beirut until Lebanon disarms Hezbollah — defense minister&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: WHO reports over 8,500 global attacks on health facilities since 2018 — director general&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Shadow of &amp;lsquo;potential brutal divorce&amp;rsquo; between Trump-Musk looms over Republicans — TV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: EU must conclude arms limitation agreement with Russia, says Orban&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Bank of Russia sells yuan worth $83 mln with settlements on June 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Attacks ahead of meeting between IAEA, Rosatom chiefs &amp;lsquo;pressure tool,&amp;rsquo; ZNPP believes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Dodon calls on Sandu, Recean not to succumb to Western attempts to drag Moldova into war&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Zelensky’s regime bears all hallmarks of terrorist organization — Russian senator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian stocks down as main trading session opens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Rosatom CEO, IAEA chief meet in Kaliningrad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukraine strikes hotel in ZNPP satellite city of Energodar with drone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukrainian army retreating from Komar community in western Donetsk region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Putin enjoys strong support among Russian people, latest poll shows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Orban sees EU bracing for another decade of countering Russia amid proxy war in Ukraine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Death toll in Ukrainian attack on Kursk Region&amp;rsquo;s Rylsk climbs to two&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia’s FAB bomb wipes out Ukrainian army platoon in southwestern Donetsk region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia to defend rights of Russian speakers in Ukraine to resolve crisis, says Lavrov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: No basis for return to START now, scenario increasingly unrealistic — MFA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US Golden Dome project could obstruct arms control, senior Russian diplomat warns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Over 80% of Russians trust Putin — poll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gazprom files new lawsuit against Naftogaz of Ukraine in Russian court&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: FACTBOX: Ukrainian UAVs attacks Russian regions in night hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: MOEX Index down 0.16% as morning trading session opens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Belgorod Region governor reports blown-up railroad tracks, no injuries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: PREVIEW: President Putin to chair session of National Projects’ Council&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukraine’s Zelensky turns terrorism into ideology of his country — Russian lawmaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Golden Dome missile shield project turns space into arena of armed confrontation — Ryabkov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: At least 12 children injured in bus accident in Russia’s Far East&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Air defenses down 10 Ukrainian drones targeting Moscow — Mayor Sobyanin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: UK engaged in search of external enemy amid domestic economic problems — diplomat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: SpaceX may decommission ISS-bound Dragon spacecraft after Trump’s statements — Musk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Israel delivers 17 strikes on Beirut’s southern suburbs — TV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia, Chad reaffirm plans to step up political dialogue — MFA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US gave Ukraine all weapons promised by Biden, former Ukrainian president says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Musk says Trump should be impeached&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Israel strikes Hezbollah targets in Beirut suburbs — IDF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Doctors examine 3 children whose mother died in shelling of Rylsk in Kursk Region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Hamas did not reject Witkoff’s latest proposal on Gaza, leader says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Uzbekistan qualifies for FIFA world cup for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump says Musk &amp;lsquo;went crazy&amp;rsquo; while leading DOGE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Almost one in three Gaza residents displaced since end of ceasefire — UN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Drone incidents at NPPs pose nuclear risk, must stop — IAEA chief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: IAEA inspectors report hearing gunfire at ZNPP, presumably targeting drones — IAEA chief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Over 90% of families in Gaza have no money to buy food — UN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Lebanese forces dismantle more than 500 military installations in country’s south — PM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Musk claims Trump would not have won presidency without him&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Far Eastern terminal to double transshipment in Vanino port&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian stock market indices mixed on Thursday — market data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian MFA says UK uses British Council to erode sovereignty of countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Israeli PM confirms enlisting Palestinian clans in Gaza to fight against Hamas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Nissan filed applications for trademarks in Russia — patent authority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Passenger transport market in Russia down 65% in 4M 2025 — Kamaz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian ambassador to UK describes Kiev’s attack on Russian airfields as escalation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Azerbaijani, Russian diplomats talk Baku-Moscow relations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian MFA warns countries against working with organizations like British Council&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: UN comments on Trump’s threats to sanction Russia, Ukraine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump says urged Putin against responding to Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s recent strikes on Russia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Slovak PM asks that Ukraine peace language be included in EU Council final statement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian bishop describes Putin-pope call as long-awaited yet jolting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump does not think Russia &amp;lsquo;playing games&amp;rsquo; in Ukraine settlement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US, China settle some disputed issues in trade — Trump&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump, Xi agree to hold new round of trade negotiations as soon as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kursk Region woman describes surviving violent attack by Ukrainian troops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump says he is ready to impose sanctions on Russia, Ukraine if no peace deal is made&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gazrom Neft develops technologies making oil lifting cheaper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gazprom Neft creates chemicals increasing oil recovery factor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia deems Radio Echo activities undesirable in country&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gas consumption in Russia rises by 5.2% in 2024 to 521.5 bcm — Gazprom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia, Iran interested in preventing tensions around Tehran’s nuclear program — MFA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukrainian military gassed civilians in Sudzha district, set fire to their homes — witness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump expects solution to Ukraine conflict to be found eventually&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US blocking Gaza resolution signifies Washington&amp;rsquo;s moral decay — Iranian MFA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gazprom increased gas supplies to Uzbekistan by 4.4 times in 2024&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia’s declining inflation opens door to easing monetary policy, lowering key rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump says venue and date of his meeting with China’s Xi to be announced later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kamaz forecasts sales of 40,000-60,000 heavy haulers in Russia this year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: West tries to prevent Russia&amp;rsquo;s return to ECOSOC with pressure — Foreign Ministry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: People in seized Kursk Region village spent nights in bushes, eyewitness says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Traces of electric shock devices found on bodies of killed civilians in Kursk Region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Over 1.6 mln Muslims performing Hajj pilgrimage to Mecca in 2025&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Authorities eyeing targeted support for coal businesses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Germany issues arrest warrant for Russian man suspected of supporting ISIS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukrainian attack kills civilian, leaves another six injured in Russia’s Kursk Region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Palestinian parliament speaker condemns US for vetoing resolution on Palestine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: In Kursk villages, many locals lost lives to Ukrainian grenades trying to shield families&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: It is essential to sustain Russia’s economic growth at least at 2%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Bank of Russia sets official dollar rate at 79.13 rubles for June 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Victim of terror attack in St. Petersburg wins $1,900 lawsuit against perpetrator Trepova&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Georgian politician demands EU bureaucrats respect republic&amp;rsquo;s sovereignty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: 10,000th Haval vehicle assembled in Kaluga Region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Donetsk official urges reporters to intensify efforts to counter Western media attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Clean Arctic project to focus on World War II memorial locations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Slovak parliament mandates Cabinet vote against new anti-Russian sanctions — news agency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Driving force behind key rate hike shielding economy from overheating reached&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Environment volunteers to have key events in Karelia along Kochkoma - Reboly road&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: Will the US Send Alleged Fuel Smugglers to Mexico?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: As Brazil’s PCC Gentrifies, Favela Residents Must Fend for Themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: On the Radar: Violence from Gangs and Governments Rules the Region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: Winner of Colombia-Ecuador Trade War Could Be Organized Crime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: Costa Rica’s Leading Presidential Candidates Embrace Hardline Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: FARC Dissidents in Venezuela&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: Organized Crime and AI: 5 Topics We Are Monitoring in 2026&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: Will Colombian Guerrillas Lose Their Safe Haven in Post‑Maduro Venezuela?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: On the Radar: Mexico Responds to US Pressure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: Álex Saab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[LATAM_Insight]&lt;/strong&gt;: How InSight Crime Tracked Down an Explosive Narco Video in Honduras&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Audio of Epstein discussing Tony Blair’s income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Global system of human rights in ‘peril’, warns HRW in its annual report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Tens of thousands evacuated as floods submerge parts of Morocco&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Citizens of Nowhere: What It Means to Be Stateless in the US&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Video shows man fighting high school students at anti-ICE protest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump’s critical minerals meet: Who’s attending, what’s at stake?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Palestinians face restrictions leaving, entering Gaza through Rafah&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: UK pro-Palestinian activists not guilty of aggravated burglary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Pakistan deploys helicopters, drones to end standoff with Baloch rebels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: ‘We are exploited’: Congolese fear losing out as US makes minerals deals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gunmen kill more than 30 people in Nigeria’s Kwara State: Authorities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gorton and Denton by-election tests Labour’s grip on heartland voters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: ‘Health crime’: Aoun slams Israel over spraying chemicals in south Lebanon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: A simple guide to playing cricket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: ICE agents have no operational police role in Winter Olympics: Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Guardiola on Palestinian struggle and ICE protests in football briefing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Can US-Iran diplomacy work? Inside the narrow window for talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: ‘No girl should ever endure what Epstein put them through’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Musk labels Spain PM ‘tyrant’ after Madrid proposes social media curbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Australian boy swims for hours in rough seas to save his family&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump hits out at reporter for question on Epstein survivors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: How Israel destroyed Gaza’s health system ‘deliberately and methodically’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: How Israel is trying to hinder NGOs from working in Gaza&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Japan chipmaker Rapidus tops $1bn in private investment as IBM aims to join&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: China outbound investment in 2025 hit highest level since 2018: report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: In Beijing, Taiwan&amp;rsquo;s KMT echoes Xi Jinping&amp;rsquo;s &amp;rsquo;national rejuvenation&amp;rsquo; call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gas turbine boom in US lifts Japan&amp;rsquo;s Mitsubishi Heavy to record profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Philippine House committee rejects Marcos impeachment complaints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Toyota plans 30% increase in global hybrid production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Prices of precious metals futures contract show significant growth on Wednesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian diplomat praises Republika Srpska leadership for resisting external pressure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: UAE expects new round of Ukraine talks to advance mutual understanding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia to continue closely monitoring Japan’s course toward remilitarization — MFA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gas prices in Europe make summer injection unprofitable — Gazprom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US hardly EU’s ally at present — senior diplomat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gas extraction from European UGS at about 742 mln cubic meters as of February 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Putin, Xi intend to meet on sidelines of SCO, BRICS summits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian budget may miss $2.73 bln in extra oil and gas revenue in February&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Musk will be imprisoned like Durov if he shows up for questioning in France — politician&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia effectively redirects gas supplies to new countries — foreign ministry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Lack of US response on New START, Putin-Xi talks: takeaways from Kremlin aide’s statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia to dig for truth in Nord Stream sabotage case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: British police identify body found in Cyprus in January as that of Russian tycoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia expects Iran-US talks to ease tensions, senior diplomat says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Oman to host Iran-US talks on February 6 — agency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia determined to continue developing comprehensive cooperation with Cuba — MFA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian Finance Ministry to sell FX and gold worth $2.96 bln in February-March&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Adyutant universal target training system is service-ready in Russia — manufacturer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia supports China&amp;rsquo;s idea for global AI organization — Kremlin aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia ranks first by oil, pipe gas supplies to China — Kremlin aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Scientists study Blue Book from first polar station on Franz Josef Land&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia expects Turkey will speak against attempts to meddle in energy cooperation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gaddafi&amp;rsquo;s son&amp;rsquo;s murder aims to undermine reconciliation — Libyan presidential council&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Belarus’ gold and FX reserves surpass record $15.7 bln&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukrainian army launches over 100 drones at Russia’s Belgorod Region in past day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Xi Jinping invites Putin to make official visit to China in first half of 2026 — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Putin ready to attend China’s APEC summit in November — Kremlin aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: No response from United States to proposal on New START yet — Kremlin aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia open to finding solutions on strategic stability — Kremlin aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Swiss foreign minister to be tried at ICC for alleged complicity in crimes in Gaza&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Depesha robot helps Battlegroup Center rescue wounded within three hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Start of consultations in Abu Dhabi determined by delegations on-site — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia, China to up communication to better respond to threats — Kremlin aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kremlin aide describes Putin-Xi talks as substantive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Putin confirms Russia’s support for One China principle — Kremlin aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia to act responsibly amid expiration of New START Treaty — Kremlin aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Mesh network for autonomous UAV navigation to be tested in Russia in 2026 — NTI Fund&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: NATO plans overt military intervention in Ukraine — Russian diplomat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Deputy chief of EU foreign policy says bloc already at war with Russia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Putin, Xi discuss blooming Russia-China relations, exemplary bilateral cooperation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia to tweak strategic blueprint amid Dutch militarization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia carries out 150 hours of maximum-tension testing of PD-8 engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kremlin plans no statements today following Abu Dhabi meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Xi calls Putin friend, says ready for dialogue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Deployment of NATO troops in Ukraine categorically unacceptable for Russia — MFA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: OMV not expecting serious gas price growth in Europe due to cold snap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Bank of Russia sells yuan worth $231 mln with settlements on February 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kremlin downplays reports about India potentially switching oil suppliers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukraine reports failure of key substations supplying country&amp;rsquo;s power grid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Euroclear to transfer 3.3 bln euros of revenues from Russian assets to Ukraine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Netherlands militarizes in push for greater NATO role — Russian embassy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: FACTBOX: New Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Pashinyan, Aliyev agree to maintain dialogue toward normalization of Yerevan-Baku ties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Exact timing of New START expiration not crucial — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Elon Musk becomes first person ever worth over $800 billion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia, France maintain only working-level contacts, no high-level talks — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Iran to restrict talks with US to nuclear issues — Bloomberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia-China partnership remains crucial for global stability — Putin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Talks on Ukraine to proceed in Abu Dhabi today — Kremlin spokesman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia grateful to US for efforts to resolve Ukrainian conflict — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Putin, Xi Jinping having confidential conversation on entire range of issues — Kremlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia’s leading energy supplier to China, Putin reiterates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: China keeps supply chains stable, expects the same from the US — Chinese embassy to US&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Press review: Russia, Ukraine talks move to new round as New START expires without renewal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Large-scale US military drills in Africa to involve around 30 countries in May&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kalashnikov Group unveils its new Goliath 2.0, Karakurt 2.0 drones at Moscow expo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukrainian negotiating team arrives in Abu Dhabi — media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia’s newest Piranha-13 kamikaze drone unveiled at Moscow exhibition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: What we know about next round of trilateral talks on Ukraine in Abu Dhabi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Rejection of New START extension could usher in new arms race — expert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia unveils Mi-34M1 helicopter at NAIS exhibition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: The cold, hungry reality of displacement in war-torn Sudan’s Tawila&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian services PMI index up to 53.1 points in January — S&amp;amp;P&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: FACTBOX: What is known about the murder of late Libyan leader’s son Saif al-Islam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: UK PM&amp;rsquo;s China trip disappoints, prompts calls for clearer strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Chinese mine machine maker quits Colombia gold project, cites geopolitics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kazakh trial of anti-China protesters highlights unequal ties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Rising Japan bond yields hit insurers but stock prices offer buffer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: India&amp;rsquo;s rising incomes lifting health care investment, Quadria says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Singapore, Hong Kong family offices favor private equity: survey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Doing business in Pakistan 34% more expensive than in regional peers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: A different kind of prime minister sparks hope among Japan&amp;rsquo;s youth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Panama Canal ports: What&amp;rsquo;s next after CK Hutchison&amp;rsquo;s concession loss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: CK Hutchison unit pursues arbitration over voided Panama port rights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Books: Japan&amp;rsquo;s space journey, from pencil rockets to Mars probes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: AMD rakes in $390m from AI chip sales to China but warns of uncertainty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: AI effect starts to flip &amp;lsquo;Korea discount&amp;rsquo; on stocks into a premium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Apple supplier Nittobo to roll out improved glass cloth crucial to AI chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Why Japan&amp;rsquo;s election matters for the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: India&amp;rsquo;s housekeeping apps tap growing demand for speedy services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Japan&amp;rsquo;s IHI to boost output of nuclear plant parts as AI drives up demand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: What bubble? Big Tech&amp;rsquo;s AI spending spree gathers pace in 2026&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: China starts paying interest on digital yuan in latest bid to extend its reach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: China&amp;rsquo;s Honor touts phone battery with double iPhone&amp;rsquo;s capacity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Takeda, Kyoto University end 10-year stem cell tie-up, with no new drugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Adani profit doubles as airports unit sees strong growth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Modi and Trump finally reach a trade deal: 5 things to know&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Eurasian states recruit high-priced US lobbyists in Trump outreach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Indian shares and rupee soar after Trump-Modi trade deal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Singapore Airshow highlights shift to sustainable fuel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Japan&amp;rsquo;s Renesas to sell timing solution segment to US-based SiTime for $3bn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Nintendo shrugs off higher chip costs, sticks to profit forecast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Indian firms welcome US trade deal after 50% tariffs dented profits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: PM Takaichi&amp;rsquo;s defense plan in sharp focus as Japan election nears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: TSMC&amp;rsquo;s American expansion is not a surrender &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s insurance for Taiwan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Nearly 40% of Japan election candidates want foreign worker curbs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Australian central bank raises key interest rate to 3.85%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Japan&amp;rsquo;s slow monetary tightening suspected of hampering yen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Qantas exits Jetstar Japan to focus on high-margin long haul routes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: The ripple effects of AI&amp;rsquo;s appetite for memory chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Thai election frontrunner People&amp;rsquo;s Party faces changing public mood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: China&amp;rsquo;s CXMT and YMTC to massively expand memory output amid global crunch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: China&amp;rsquo;s Shenghe feuds with Australian rare-earth partner in Greenland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: ASEAN insurer offering governments disaster cover gains traction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ho Chi Minh City tests drones for deliveries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: China&amp;rsquo;s rare-earth miners hit by price headwinds, eroding profits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Thailand&amp;rsquo;s Central Group targets rich Japan shoppers with tie-up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Mitsubishi Chemical to exit steelmaking coke business amid China glut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: SoftBank, Fanuc turn to partners as robotics and AI merge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump, Modi reach trade deal that cuts tariffs on Indian goods to 18%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Indonesian coffee chains brew stronger overseas ambitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Iran&amp;rsquo;s proxy groups are ready for a wider existential war&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Japanese herbal liqueur maker Yomeishu to delist and sell operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Asia_Nikkei]&lt;/strong&gt;: Overseas Japanese schools struggle as student numbers fall 20% in 10 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Israel suspends evacuation of Palestinians via Rafah crossing: Red Crescent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Yamal scores as Barcelona beat Albacete to reach Copa del Rey semifinals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: James Harden traded from Clippers to Cavaliers for Darius Garland: Reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Man City’s Guardiola says he will continue to stand up for Palestine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: ‘Heavily armed’: Greece, Israel boost military ties amid Gaza genocide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: ‘No expectations’: Bangladesh election means little to 1m Rohingya refugees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump says talks with Iran continuing amid tensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia-Ukraine war: Second round of peace talks set to begin in Abu Dhabi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: LIVE: Israel ‘suspends’ evacuation of patients through Rafah crossing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: China warns Panama as Hong Kong firm contests ruling on canal ports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Thousands march in Venezuela to demand US free President Maduro, wife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: ‘A great honor’: Key takeaways from Trump’s meeting with Colombia’s Petro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Bus crashes in Brazil’s Alagoas state, killing at least 16 people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Palestinian women recount ‘journey of horror’ at Gaza’s Rafah crossing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia-Ukraine war: List of key events, day 1,441&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: These exiled Venezuelans dream of returning home. What’s stopping them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Collision between Greek coastguard vessel, migrant boat kills at least 14&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: US House passes $1.2 trillion spending package to end government shutdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Who was Saif al-Islam Gaddafi, the man once seen as Libya’s next leader?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Sudan’s military breaks through years-long RSF blockade in Kadugli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Saif al-Islam Gaddafi, son of Libyan former leader, killed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: ‘Game is over’: Iran’s ex-leaders, hardliners clash after protest killings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Son of Norway’s crown princess pleads not guilty in rape case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: UN chief urges Gaza aid as Israel blocks most medical evacuees at Rafah&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Medio_Oriente]&lt;/strong&gt;: Walmart hits trillion dollar market cap for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukraine seeks to discuss ceasefire in Abu Dhabi talks — agency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Armenian PM, Azerbaijani leader discuss implementation of Trump Route in Abu Dhabi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Tor air defense missile systems deployed to protect important facilities — manufacturer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia launches production of Tor-M2KM air defense system’s seaborne version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian stock indices rise as main trading session opens on Moscow Exchange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Serial production of Russia&amp;rsquo;s first domestic engine for heavy-lift UAVs to start in Feb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Canada has no plans to pursue nuclear weapons, defense chief says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Witkoff lands in Abu Dhabi for talks on Ukraine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Marine engine for combat missions successfully tested in St. Petersburg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukrainian army launches HIMARS rockets, Neptune missiles, drones at Bryansk Region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian troops start using Germes anti-drone MANPADS in special military op zone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Creation of Eurasian security architecture requires broad cooperation, expert says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Over 10,000 weapons enter into service with Russian Army in January — defense chief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Libyan prosecutors confirm Gaddafi’s son death from gunshot wounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Azerbaijani leader, Armenian PM meet in Abu Dhabi — news agency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Putin-Trump accord could restart arms control process — US expert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Abu Dhabi to host new round of consultations on Ukraine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Air defenses destroy 24 Ukrainian drones over Russian regions overnight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Macron missed his chance for talks with Putin — US expert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US may slap Algeria with sanctions for purchasing Russian fighter jets — diplomat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Strategic stability requires peace in Ukraine — US expert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Damage from corruption crimes tops $207 million last year — Russian ministry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US believes Russia can easily boost nuclear potential when New START expires&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US agrees to negotiate with Iran in Oman, talks possibly due on February 6 — Axios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Musk describes search at X office in France as political attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Dozen of powerful solar flares registered on February 3 — scientists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gaddafi’s son will not be buried until murder investigation finished&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Social network X says searches in Paris office baseless, denies all accusations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Ukrainian energy minister says situation in Kiev critical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Israel conveyed its Iran-related demands to US — TV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Netanyahu, Witkoff discuss Hamas disarmament, situation around Iran&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Plans for meeting of US, Iranian officials still in force — Trump&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: NATO’s European command starts planning Arctic Sentry operation — Spiegel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian economy to be more efficient by creating decent jobs — Putin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Witkoff, Kushner to take part in trilateral talks on Ukraine in UAE on February 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump says Russia’s one-week energy ceasefire was important step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump says he noted need for Ukrainian settlement during talks with Putin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Estonian authorities detain commercial vessel with Russian sailors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian UN envoy expresses concern over UN chief’s statements on Crimea, Donbass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Lawyer of Gaddafi’s son confirms his death — portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Imported case of chikungunya virus registered in Russia — watchdog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Muscat likely to be chosen as venue for Iran-US talks — TV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian negotiators touch down in Abu Dhabi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Iran, US discussing date, venue for talks — MFA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Gaddafi&amp;rsquo;s son killed in attack in his home&amp;rsquo;s courtyard — TV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump not surprised by Russia&amp;rsquo;s response to Kiev&amp;rsquo;s attacks, focuses on diplomacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US military shoots down Iranian drone over Arabian Sea — agency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: G7 issued $37.9 billion in loans to Ukraine from Russian frozen assets in 2025&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia can play key role in overcoming Iranian crisis — US expert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Infrastructure facility damaged in Ukraine’s missile attack on Belgorod&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Opposition politician slams president Sandu&amp;rsquo;s Nobel Peace Prize nomination as farce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian stock indices up as main trading session on Moscow Exchange closes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Effect of structural changes in economy to be seen as early as in 2026 — Putin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia sets its goals, objectives for G20 — Foreign Ministry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian GDP add 1% in 2025 — Putin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Source confirms negotiations on Ukraine to take place on February 4-5 in Abu Dhabi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Inflation managed to be lowered to 5.6% by 2025 year-end — Putin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Nissan registers Infiniti trademark in Russia — watchdog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia defends its interests based on historical experience and to be heard — official&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia believes in keeping divisive politics out of sports — presidential aide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia never refused contacts with German partners — embassy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Turkey ready to serve as mediator between Iran, US, will continue contacts — Erdogan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Armenia&amp;rsquo;s CSTO membership no obstacle to buying weapons elsewhere — former president&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Georgian parliament approves amendments to law aimed at preventing funding of unrest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Witkoff and Netanyahu hold meeting in Jerusalem — newspaper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Corporate funds in Russian banks up by 0.7% in December to $818 bln — regulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: FIFA chief Infantino’s words about Russia deserve special attention — Russian official&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian is one of eight working languages to be used at 2026 Winter Olympics in Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian national accused of terrorism extradited from Morocco&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Share of foreign investments in Russian federal loan bonds growing to 3.4% last December&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Household funds in Russian banks up by 5.6% in December — regulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia plans to cooperate with CIS countries to establish historical truth — Malysheva&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Historical memory may become national priority for Russia — official&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: IN BRIEF: What we know about Epstein files and reaction to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: India&amp;rsquo;s immediate halt of Russian oil import is &amp;rsquo;extremely unlikely&amp;rsquo; — newspaper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian GDP growth in 2025 to be close to lower limit of forecast range — Central Bank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Inflation lowering to 4%, stabilization requires tough monetary policy — Bank of Russia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Rutte is &amp;rsquo;telling tales&amp;rsquo; when promising NATO troops in Ukraine — Russian legislator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: NATO chief’s statements hinder peace settlement in Ukraine — Russian MP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: India reduces Russian oil purchases since end of last year — US Trade Representative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US to lift 25% tariffs imposed on India for oil purchases from Russia — WP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: US President Donald Trump could leverage Epstein files to his advantage, expert says&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Deal with India to be similar to US trade agreements with other countries — Reuters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Bank of Russia lowers official dollar rate for February 4 to 76.98 rubles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian-Cambodian military cooperation group meets at Russian Defense Ministry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: NATO seeks to give Kiev more air defense missiles beyond those from US — Rutte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Armenian parliament speaker to meet with top Russian diplomat during visit to Moscow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: One-third of NATO countries do not participate in purchasing US arms for Ukraine — Rutte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Coal exports by rail in Russia down 0.3% to 177 mln tons in 2025&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: FSB detains foreigner preparing explosion at Moscow Region power facility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: OPEC+ expects oil demand to rise in spring and summer — Novak&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia grateful to Myanmar for its position on Ukraine — top security official&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia, Belarus, Iran, North Korea, Myanmar to hold consultations on Eurasian Charter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russian journalists to work under neutral status at 2026 Olympics in Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Kazakhstan’s new draft constitution puts border speculation to rest — advisor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Each fifth nuclear plant worldwide operates on Rosatom’s equipment — Deputy CEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Russia&amp;rsquo;s overnight strikes do big damage to Ukrainian power grid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Norway’s parliament votes to maintain monarchy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: Hungary is only EU country to maintain ties with Russia, US, China, Turkey — minister&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Rusia_Eurasia]&lt;/strong&gt;: More than 1,100 apartment buildings in Kyiv left without heating — mayor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>